We are gathered here today
to immortalise in song
the life and untimely death
of a great legend.
- Rango.
- So sit back, relax,
and enjoy your low-calorie popcorn
and assorted confections
while we tell you the strange
and bewildering tale of a hero
who has yet to enter his own story.
Crunchy, creamy, cookie,
candy, cupcake.
Okay, everybody,
let's take it from the top.
The stage is set,
the night moist with apprehension.
Alone in her chamber, the princess
prepares to take her own life.
"It is far better to nourish worms
than to live without love."
She reaches for the poisoned chalice.
Meanwhile, the wicked Malvolio
plots his ascension to the throne
while her ageing father lies gravely ill.
"Yes, I am gravely ill."
"Hark, who goes there?"
'Tis I, the much-anticipated hero,
returning to rescue
his emotionally unstable maiden!
Unhand her, you jailers of virtue,
or taste the bitter sting
of my vengeance!
The sting of my...
Dr Marx?
Dr Marx,
I'm not getting anything from you.
People, we've talked about this.
Acting is reacting.
Victor, you were wooden!
There, I said it.
Mr Timms? You were good.
Perhaps a little too good.
What's that, Victor? My character's
undefined? That's absurd.
I know who I am.
I'm the guy, the protagonist, the hero.
Every story needs a hero.
I mean, who else is better qualified
to bask in the adulation
of his numerous companions?
The stage is waiting.
The audience thirsts for adventure.
Who am I?
I could be anyone.
I could be the sea cap'n
returning from a mighty voyage
to reclaim his mechanical arm!
Or I could be the rogue anthropologist,
battling pythons down in the Congo!
Down, Chongo, down!
And if you desire romance,
I will become the greatest lover
the world has ever known!
I couldn't help but notice you
noticing me noticing you.
You know, the womens find me
uncomfortably good looking.
But you seem remarkably at ease.
Stop it. No, really.
Well, if you must. What are you doing?
That tickles. Are those real?
That's it! Conflict.
Victor, you were right.
I have been undefined.
People, I've had an epiphany.
The hero cannot exist in a vacuum!
What our story needs is an ironic,
unexpected event
that will propel the hero into conflict!
Mr Timms?
That's right! You!
Don't be shy. Come on.
It's okay.
That's it, a little closer.
Good.
I won't bite you.
I need a little help here.
Are you okay?
I must get to the other side.
The other side? You mean, just now,
that was you crossing the road?
That's why the...
Why'd you do that?
This is my quest. He waits for me.
What? Who?
The Spirit of the West,
amigo. The one.
They say he rides an alabaster carriage
with golden guardians to protect him.
What are you talking about?
Enlightenment.
We are nothing without it.
Nothing? Your delusional quest
just ruined my life!
I had an incredibly complex
social network going!
Highly sophisticated friends!
I was very popular!
Friends? I don't see no friends.
You are a very lonely lizard.
Now help me up
and I will help you find what you seek.
- You will?
- Quickly. I must get back to my quest.
- You mean you've done this before?
- Yes. Many times.
Come, come. That's it, pull my finger.
The Spirit is waiting for me.
Okay, okay.
Okay. That's not going to work.
I must get to the other side.
Why don't you just wait
until there are no cars coming?
It's not so easy as it looks.
What?
Is a metaphor.
There's another one!
I knew it.
You need a little help, amigo?
I think the metaphor broke my spleen.
The path to knowledge
is fraught with consequence.
I'm just looking for the path to water.
If you want to find water,
you must first find Dirt.
Dirt.
Destiny, she is kind to you.
Tomorrow is Wednesday.
The water comes.
At noon, the townspeople gather
for a mysterious ritual.
A town? You mean, with real people
and everything? Where?
A day's journey. Follow your shadow.
You want me to just walk out
into the desert?
That's the way.
Okay. So you're saying
there's a town, a real town,
not a metaphor town.
Go on. It's okay.
Okay.
Well, then, I'm going.
I am leaving the road now!
I'm walking into the desert!
Alone!
We all have our journeys to make!
I will see you on the other side.
Welcome, amigo
To the land without end
The desert and death
Are the closest of friends
We sing of his courage
In magnificent song
But pay close attention
He won't be here long
As the birds pluck his eyes
The sun bleaches his bones
See his entrails get scattered
Watch him lose his cojones
Here in the Mojave Desert,
animals have had millions of years
to adapt to the harsh environment.
But the lizard? He is going to die.
"Four score and seven years ago,
our fathers..."
- Don't move.
- What?
- Don't move!
- Not moving.
Not moving.
Try to blend in.
Blend in? What do you mean?
Blend in.
What are you saying?
- Too late.
- No, no. It's not too late!
I'm blending! I'm a blender!
Hey, calm down! What are you doing?
Stop moving!
Try not to look conspicuous.
- What are you doing?
- I'm blending.
- Go blend somewhere else.
- Don't distract me.
- No room at the inn.
- It's an art, not a science.
- Find your own hiding place.
- No, this is good.
Here she comes! You better run, Mojito!
- What? I thought you said, "Don't move."
- That was before. Now, you run.
Oh, hey. Proboscis.
Testy.
Please, no, please. I have vertigo!
My glands are swelling!
Please, no.
You! I'll kill you! You stupid lizard!
Get out of there.
I'm going to strangle your huevos!
Big bird! Big bird!
No, wait! Come back! I was just kidding!
- Come on, we're friends, right?
- I don't know you!
- Lizards, frogs...
- Find your own hiding place!
- We're practically related!
- No room at the inn!
- Come on, move over!
- You're not my friend!
I'll let you kiss my sister!
You son of a...
Where are your friends now, amigo?
Get your slimy-webbed phalanges
off my boots!
Sorry.
I got a bead on you, stranger.
So you get up real slow
lessen you want to spend the better part
of the afternoon
putting your face back together!
- No, ma'am, I don't.
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
- I'm asking the questions here!
Our town is drying up.
We're in the middle of a drought.
Now someone's dumping water
in the desert!
It's a puzzle of undeterminable size
and dimension,
but I intend to find out
what role you playing in all this.
- Role?
- What are you involved in?
Well, I'm glad you asked.
I've got two one-acts, a mystery
and a musical I've been gestating.
I got the words, I'm just working on
the melody right now. It's like a...
I think it's gonna be a western.
A monkey got a cracker
His mother was a slapper
She'll be coming 'round the mountain
in the rain
You ain't from around here, are you?
I'm still working on it.
So, what's your name?
- Beans.
- That's a funny kind of name.
What can I say?
My daddy plumb loved baked beans.
Well, you're lucky
he didn't plumb love asparagus.
What are you saying?
I mean,
I enjoy a hearty puttanesca myself,
but I'm not sure that a child
would appreciate the moniker.
My daddy was a great man, even if
he did exhibit a proclivity for legumes.
- Spicy.
- You're eating his ashes!
You carry his remains?
No, his ashes. He loved to smoke.
They never found the body.
Well, I'm sure he had his reasons.
- What are you implying?
- Nothing.
My daddy was never near
that mine shaft.
He'd been sober for over a month!
And for you to insinuate that he would
abandon his parental responsibilities
at a delicate time in my personal
development is an affront to my sense...
Miss Beans?
Miss Beans? Hello?
Hello?
And until the people of Andromeda Five
return him safe and sound,
I will not sell my ranch!
- What... What are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- What am I doing?
- You're cuddling me.
- You were frozen.
- I was not.
Yes, you were. You stopped talking.
It's a defence mechanism.
Actually, lots of lizards have it.
You're making that up.
So, you gonna die out here,
or you want a ride into town?
No, no, no. Yeah. No. Yes, please.
Thank you. Sorry.
Today's Wednesday.
Wednesday's when we all get to it.
So who are you, really?
Well, I'm a man of many epithets.
There's my stage name, my pen name,
my avatar.
I had a pseudonym once,
but I had it legally changed.
And so the stranger,
seeking companionship,
finds the woman,
much like the sirens of ancient times
luring him to his certain demise.
...nom de plume, I have a CB handle.
I'm actually one of the few men
with a maiden name.
Whoa! Well, here we are.
Right.
Well, I sure do appreciate this,
Miss Beans,
- and if there's ever anything that I...
- Get on up!
Okay, then!
See you, Beans.
You heading out, Jim?
Well, we gave it our best shot.
We had to sell out.
Can't grow no crops without no water.
Bye, now!
What is it?
What was that for?
You're funny looking.
Oh, yeah?
Well, you're funny looking, too.
- That's a funny-looking shirt.
- That's a funny-looking dress.
- You got funny-looking eyes!
- You got a funny-looking face!
You're a stranger.
Strangers don't last long here.
Here's your beans, Beans.
I'm gonna need some more feed, too,
Willie.
Now, Beans, you owe me three quarts
already. I can't give you more credit.
But I'll have what I owe you at noon.
You don't understand. It's Mr Merrimack
down at the bank. He cut off all credit.
Hey, Beans! Beans!
You know that there fella?
Hey, Beans! Miss Beans!
Nope.
Hey, Beans!
Hey.
Right. Blend in. Yeah, blend in.
I'd like a glass of water.
He wants a glass of water!
Make it a double!
Give him the spittoon!
Cactus juice. That's what we got.
Hey, there, fruit cup.
You're a long ways from home, ain't ya?
Who exactly are you?
Who am I?
I could be anyone.
What's the matter?
You missing your mommy's mangos?
As a matter of fact, I am.
But not as much as
your daddy's cooking!
Exactly where did you say
you were from?
Me? I'm from the West.
Out there, beyond the horizon.
Past the sunset.
The Far West.
Yeah, that's right, hombres.
The place I come from,
we kill a man before breakfast
just to work up an appetite.
Then we salt him, and we pepper him.
Then we braise him in clarified butter.
And then we eat him.
- You eat him?
- That's what I said!
Hell, I seen things make a grown man
lose control of his glandular functions!
You spend three days in a horse
carcass, living off your own juices.
It'll change a man. Oh, yeah.
Had a few extra aces in this deck,
gents. Just the way I like it.
So, no, my hirsute little rodent friend,
I am not from around these parts.
You might say I'm from everywhere
there's trouble brewing
and hell waiting to be raised.
You might say
I'm what hell's already raised up.
Name's
Rango.
Are you the fella
that killed them Jenkins brothers?
Killed them with one bullet.
Don't get no deader.
All seven of them?
That's right.
All seven of them.
Exactly how you do that, Mr Rango?
You know, I'm glad you asked me that.
And I will be happy to tell you how.
But you're all gonna have to listen up!
Because this is where it gets
complicated.
That'll close out your account,
Mrs Oats, two gulps and a swig.
Hands off, Mordecai! That's what's left
of your college education!
I don't rightly have
no other choice, Beans.
Times being so hard,
we just can't give no more credit.
But this here is a bank.
This is where you keep the water.
Beans, you've been like a niece to me
ever since your daddy
did not fall drunk down a mine shaft.
I've tried to protect you and others
from certain realities.
But that... Well...
- Mr Merrimack?
- Realities are bearing down.
Mr Merrimack!
Are you all right?
Beans, I need to show you something.
- That's all that's left?
- And this here is the reserve!
I don't know if you've noticed,
but folks just ain't making deposits
on a Wednesday no more!
Mr Merrimack, if I don't get some water,
I'm gonna lose my ranch
and you're telling me
that's all that's left in the whole town?
Now that just don't make no sense.
Now, listen.
Someone is dumping water
in the desert.
I seen it with my own eyes.
Water in the desert?
Was this during
one of your special times?
No.
Well, we can all dream,
but this is the reality.
Why do you think so many people
are selling out? They just can't make it.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
Well, I suppose
we could talk to the Mayor.
I hear he's been helping people out
in this time of crisis.
The Mayor?
He may be our only hope.
Bullet hits a shovel, ricochets back
towards number three,
and that's when the roof caved in,
igniting the thermos
of pure grain alcohol
instantly vapourising his bodily form,
leaving nothing but a charcoal statue
and a high-pitched squeal.
Hold on, there. That's only six.
What happened to number seven?
Number seven?
Hell, he died of infection.
- Seven men!
- One bullet!
Drinks all around!
Dance for me, Sod Buster!
- Yes, dance like a chicken!
- That's right! Dance!
You got corn in your ears, mate?
You don't pay the mortgage,
you don't own the land!
- That's basic real estate law, my friend.
- Quid pro quo!
If I see your face in this town again,
I'm gonna slice it off and use it
to wipe my unmentionables.
Mind the beak.
And don't come back!
What are you all gawping at?
Hey, Bad Bill,
there's something I got to tell you!
What is this?
You know who that is, Bill?
That there's Rango!
Yeah, he ain't afraid of you!
He ain't afraid of none of you.
Killed them Jenkins brothers.
- Done it with one bullet, Bill.
- All seven of them!
Is that right?
Let me get that before you...
No. Oh, I know. Here.
Just take care of that for you.
There. All better.
T.O. T.O. Just a second.
All right, now listen!
I'm going to give you fellas
one last chance to reconsider!
And if you don't want to reconsider
I might consider reconsidering myself.
Now that's what I'm talking about. Yeah.
All right, now listen up!
Things are going to be different
around here now that Rango's in town.
Got some new rules!
I want my shoes shined every morning,
my coffee hot, Danish on the side.
Whatever you do,
don't look me in the eye.
Stay out of my peripheral vision!
- It's Rango.
- What's he up to?
He ain't afraid of nobody.
He's telling that bird what's for!
And when you see me coming,
stand aside.
I take large steps and I don't want
none of you hayseeds
getting your bodily fluids on my boots!
Of course, there is no need for violence,
as long as we stick together,
work as a team.
So I want you all to come outside now
and line up single file
while I take a brief intermission!
What's he doing now?
I think it's a number two.
Never mind.
Take a look-see over here!
Well, look at him now!
He's chasing after that hawk!
Give him hell, Rango!
- Did you see that?
- He killed that thing!
What do you think, Doc?
This hawk is dead!
Shoot, I say we cook that right up.
He did it with one bullet!
Just like he said!
It's about time
we had a hero around here.
One who ain't in a pine box.
I think it's time he met the Mayor.
You hear that, Rango?
You're going to meet the Mayor!
Let's hear it for Rango!
And so the stranger basks
in the adulation of his new friends,
sinking deeper into the guacamole
of his own deception.
When is he going to die?
Soon, compadre. Soon.
My land is not for sale!
I came here to save my land, not sell it!
I'm sure there's something reasonable
we can work out if you just talk to him!
Beans! Where are you going? Beans?
The Mayor will see you now.
Water, Mr Rango, water.
Without it,
there's nothing but dust and decay.
But with water there's life.
Look at them, so desperate to live,
they'll follow it anywhere.
That's the immutable law of the desert.
Control the water
and you control everything.
This is from my private stock.
Vintage rainwater
from the Great Deluge.
Not Noah's deluge.
Good heavens, I'm not that old.
I guess power has its privileges.
You make a good point, son.
But with privilege comes responsibility.
Hell, I was mayor here
before there was a Dirt!
And I may be
just a sentimental old turtle
but I think there's a future for this town.
And I hope you'll be part of it.
- To Dirt!
- To Dirt.
You see them, Mr Rango?
All my friends and neighbours?
It's a hard life here. Very hard.
Do you know how they make it through
each and every day?
They believe.
They believe it's going to be better.
They believe that the water will come.
They believe against all odds
and all evidence
that tomorrow will be better than today.
People have to believe in something.
Right now, they believe in you.
Pick it up, Mr Rango.
Your destiny awaits.
People have to believe in something.
It just don't make no sense.
This whole town is drying up,
and the Mayor is the only one
who don't seem to be affected.
Doesn't that make you
just a wee bit suspicious?
And what about that water
I saw out in the desert?
All right! No need to incite anxiety.
I'll inquire about the Mayor.
But if you really feel
there's some conspiracy occurring,
I suggest you take it up
with the new sheriff.
This is going to be good. Hey!
Watch that needle there.
Not too tight.
I want to leave room for some pucker!
That's good.
Oh, easy there, tiger.
- A little up and back?
- I don't think so.
Have you got French cuffs with that?
Excuse me, Sheriff Rango.
I want to talk to you.
Hey, Beans,
what do you think of the new duds?
I got a 10-gallon hat
marked down from 15.
- That's nice.
- Have you met Angelique?
- Hello, Beans.
- Hello, Angelique.
- Tart.
- Floozy.
- Trollop.
- Excuse me, Mr Rango.
I will blow that ugly right off your face!
I was just thinking that...
You want the old John Hancock,
do you?
- Well, here. Hold this.
- Sheriff Rango, this isn't a social call.
There's a bullet in there.
I know about the shindig this afternoon.
- I ordered myself some right fancy duds.
- Sheriff, I'd like to file a...
- Mr Rango!
- Oh, you, too? No problem.
- Here, let me just...
- I need you to investigate...
You know, Beans, I bet you clean up
real nice, you put a little effort into it.
- What?
- Now, remember, son,
stay in school, eat your veggies,
burn everything but Shakespeare.
- Who's Shakespeare?
- Sheriff Rango,
if that is your real name.
I am trying to save my daddy's ranch,
which is on the verge
of an agricultural meltdown
while you're playing patty-cake
with this here trollop!
Sad, really. Such a drab little thing.
Why does she do that?
- It's a survival reflex.
- Her switch is just broken.
Well, that's an inconvenience.
It is not a rash! It is a birthmark!
I did it again, didn't I?
Did what?
Let me ask you something.
Did anybody here mention
what happened to our last sheriff?
Pardon, but may I ask you...
Excuse me, may I ask you...
The last sheriff... Pardon me.
Where is everybody going?
What exactly happened to the...
All day
I've faced the barren waste
Without the taste of water
Cool water
Old Dan and I
With throats burned dry
And souls that cry
For water
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Cool
Clear water
This is a heck of a hoedown
you got going.
Still working out those steps.
So, is this considered
normal civic behaviour?
Every Wednesday, just like clockwork.
You kill bird.
Yeah. Matter of fact, I did.
Bird dead. Snake come.
Snake?
He means Rattlesnake Jake, Mr Rango.
He never comes to town 'cause
he's scared of that hawk.
But he might come now.
Can I have your boots
when you're dead?
No!
And I ain't got no problem
with this Rattlesnake Jake.
That's just what Amos said.
Amos?
You got any gold fillings?
My fellow Dirtonians.
I welcome you to our great day
of deliverance. Hallelujah.
- Hallelujah!
Acolytes, prepare the holy spigot!
We have a newcomer
amongst us today, my friends.
A man I think needs
little introduction to you
so bold has been his entry
into our fair society.
Mr Rango, would you step forward?
The time has come, my friends.
The time that was foretold!
- Hallelujah!
The sacred time!
The time of destiny!
- Hallelujah!
The time of deliverance!
It is the time of hydration!
- It's his fault!
- It's the newcomer!
- Burn him!
- He's a witch!
I get his boots!
My friends, my friends!
Temper your frustrations.
Times will be tough from now on.
Sacrifices will have to be made.
But if I can help in any way,
please know that my door is always...
Hold it, hold it!
Now, this whole thing
stinks three ways to Sunday.
First the bank's run dry
and now this here spigot?
The bank's run dry?
- What's she talking about?
- She said there's no water in the bank!
This is all we have!
We can't give it all out!
That was my rehydration account!
None of that civil disobedience
in my town, thank you very much.
Thank goodness you're here, Sheriff.
Things were getting out of hand.
Come right in.
Let me have a gander at the source
of the societal discontentment here.
Mercy.
All right, listen up! I've been thinking
and I believe I've figured something out.
You folks have a water problem!
Now just pay attention, everybody.
I'm trying to make a point here.
Let's say this fella here
were to take a drink of water.
Just one little drink.
No harm, no foul, right?
And you!
You're just as dried up and parched
as a jackrabbit in July.
So you belly on up
and take you a double shot!
Stay with me.
What do you think happens then?
Why we'd all be drinking!
And before you know it,
there wouldn't be any more water.
And then where would we be?
We'd be thirsty.
Real thirsty.
We'd turn on each other
like a bunch of animals!
Now look here.
We have got six days of water.
We have got five days...
As long as we've got water,
we've got ourselves a town.
Sheriff Rango is right.
As long as we have this water,
we have some hope.
And you can all take it from me.
My 100% full-time employment
from this moment on
will be to protect
our precious natural resource.
Ain't no one gonna tango
with the Rango.
Evening, ladies.
Evening, Sheriff.
And don't you come back!
Hold on there, Gordy. You get back
in there and you assert yourself,
and I think you'll find the people of this
here town to be surprisingly hospitable.
Thank you, Sheriff.
What? Not you again!
I stand corrected.
- This ain't the bank.
- I told you, Jedidiah!
Hold it right there!
- Who's that?
- It's the Sheriff!
Get them hands up
where I can see them!
Just as I suspected.
Prospecting without the authorised
equipment. Don't move a muscle.
Prospecting?
Now, you got your shovel,
pickaxe, Benadryl, loofah,
assorted snacks, some puzzle books
and you're gonna need a permit.
- Loofah.
- Ezekiel, Jedidiah!
What the Sam Hill's going on up there?
I've had polyps removed
smarter than the two of you!
Hell's fire, this ain't the bank!
Pappy, the Sheriff is standing right here,
helping us out.
Gonna give us a permit for prospecting.
That's right, sir. Just doing my duty.
The lonely constable on his rounds,
keeping an eagle eye out
for mayhem and malfeasance.
Does he look like he sounds?
Well, Sheriff,
if we was to hit the mother lode,
being prospectors and such,
where would we deposit said annuity?
Here in the town of Dirt,
we happen to have
the finest financial institution
this side of the Missouri.
Protected morning, noon and night
by yours truly.
Much obliged.
The bank's been robbed!
Good Lord, the bank's been robbed!
What's going on?
- It's gone! The water's all gone!
- What'd he say?
He said the bank's been robbed!
Dr Marx! I'm on fire! Embrace me!
The bank's been robbed, the town is dry
"We'll die of thirst," the people cry
He promised to protect the vault
The water's gone, it's all his fault
All right, folks, stand back,
clear the area.
This is a crime scene now.
Secure the perimeter, dust for prints,
check for fibres, scan for DNA.
I want a urine sample from everyone.
And get me a latte.
And don't mix up the two.
What's this?
"Prospecting Permit."
I'll take that. Material evidence.
What are we gonna do now, Sheriff?
- We need that water.
- We're all going to die!
My friends, we all know
what we have to do now.
That's right.
We all know what we have to do now.
- And that would be?
- Form a posse.
Form a possum!
A posse.
Now, we're gonna be doing this
in an orderly fashion.
First off, does anybody here know
how to use a firearm of any kind?
All right, then.
What do we do now, Sheriff?
Now we ride!
Where are we going?
What?
Now, as my deputy, you'll be in charge
of all tracking and finding of villains,
utilising your well-developed
Injun-uity, no offence taken.
So which way do you think they went?
You want to sniff the air or commune
with a buffalo or something?
Oh, you're good.
I'm depending on you, Spoons.
You got a little tobaccy
in the beard there.
Always good to have a medical man
along, Doc.
Reptiles got to stick together, right,
my brother?
I'm an amphibian.
Ain't no shame in that.
You sure you're
fit for duty there, soldier?
Well, you got a little something
in your eye there.
Oh, that? That there's conjunctivitis, sir.
It's hereditary.
Well, I'm glad to hear
it's not contagious.
Now, just wait a cotton-picking minute!
A posse ain't no place for a...
Never mind.
Hold on there, little sister.
Someone's gonna have
to look after the town while I'm gone.
Can I gut-shoot someone?
Let's put a pin in that.
Sheriff, you're going to bring
that water back, aren't you?
Count on it, little sister.
- Which way do we go, Sheriff?
- There's tunnels everywhere.
Whole town's perforated with them.
How'd them fellers
find the bank, anyway?
Gentlemen, if we can just
stay on task here.
Sheriff! Over here!
- Would you look at that?
- Like seeing the face of God.
Amen, brother.
I remember when it used to flow
every Wednesday.
Those were the halcyon days.
Must be a reason she quit on us.
Whatever the reason,
something is controlling this here water.
What do you say, Sheriff?
Clearly, the robbers came
from this direction.
I say we track this pipe
back to its hydraulic origin
and apprehend the culprits
behind this aquatic conundrum.
- What'd he say?
- I think he said follow the pipe.
- He said follow the pipe.
Whatever you do, do not look down.
- What is this place?
- It's an aquifer.
What's an aquifer?
Well, it's for aqua.
Well, it's empty now.
That's a big one.
- It's the end of the line.
- Don't go no further.
Someone or something
is messing with our hydration
and that pipe
has got something to do with it.
I thought
we was following bank robbers!
We're experiencing a paradigm shift.
I'm gonna shift the features on your face
if you don't shut up!
Go ahead and try!
Quiet, you savages! Stop your rattling.
You're affecting my cogitation.
Whoa! I got it. Snuff out them torches.
Sure enough.
Smart thinking there, feller.
- Start climbing.
- Get your foot out of my face!
Not bad, huh, Beans?
You keep thinking like that,
your hat's gonna catch on fire.
Well, you know, you get on a roll,
you just...
Hot, hot! Burn.
Poor things.
All they wanted was a little water.
Cactus dying of thirst. It don't bode well.
- Hey, look what I found!
- What you got there?
- I saw that first!
- Hey, that's mine!
Give me that!
It's empty anyway.
I knew that.
Where'd you find that?
Sheriff! You're going to want to see this!
It's Mr Merrimack from the bank.
What's he doing here?
- Everybody stand back.
- All right, let me see.
Looks like them varmints shot him
in the back.
No, this man wasn't shot.
He was drowned!
- Drowned?
- In the middle of the desert?
What a way to go.
Well, now, whose boot prints are those?
That's interesting.
The ground's still wet.
I suppose we should bury him.
- I don't know. Birds got to eat, too.
- Circle of life!
Hey! What's that dad-gum Indian doing?
I see you're consulting with the spirits.
No, I'm moulting.
Means I'm ready to mate.
I'll keep that in mind.
Cactus fruit.
Ah, yes. The ancient cactus fruit.
I believe your people use it
as seasoning
when preparing your native dishes.
Also natural laxative.
Pick up trail.
Three men heading west.
One blind, one with
enlarged prostate, riding sidesaddle.
- What did he say?
- They're riding sidesaddle.
- We're whispering.
- What'd he say?
Someone's got a bad valve.
All right, which one of you fellers
needs a check-up?
Awkward.
What exactly are we going to do now?
Now we ride!
That means we're riding now!
This moment.